

26 year track records in Hotel/Hospitality business, qualified as Hotel General Manager, Business Development / Constructions and pre openings experience/Consulting & Investment director

General management experience in sales & Marketing. People management and strong leadership skills, Self-starter and success minded and results orientated culture operations and clients servicing, looking to assist in this business future growth, overseas or International experience.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **EXECUTIVE MANAGEMENT**

### **ACCOMMODATION MANAGER**

# JVACEE – JOIN VENTURE ARAB CONTRACTOR & ELSWEEDY ELECTRIC Aug 2020 – Present JULUS NYARERE HYDROPOWER PROJECT TANZANIA (NATIONAL PROJECT)

- Care of entire employees in the Camp. Manage the attendance, arranging transportation, conflict management, materials handling. Almost 6000 people at camps currently 4200 residence
- Responsible for purchasing necessary stocks for the camp.
- Responsible for complying with all the Government regulations and inspections at camp Responsible for all aspects of the internal soft services operations at the project.
- Day-to-day staff management, consultant, and client liaison.
- · Ambassador for the Project.
- Work closely with the consultant and client representative.
- Improve, enhance and manage all internal soft services tasks.
- Recruiting, training other staff.
- Manage the team of expatriates' staff working at the camp and increase his motivation
- Responsible for requests made to the warehouse, as per the department's request of stocking and stock checking
- Providing the requested stocks to the departments and deliver stock with the help of the company driver
- Keep Camps look clean, tidy, and should follow diligently the disciplinary rules laid out in his contract.
- Keep a record of the weekly activities report and sent it to the main office, with all documents.
- Fill the Local staff Timesheet and attendance register.
- Responsible for the effective cleaning of the kitchen, the dining area, and stores, following the Food Hygiene and Safety rules.
- Ensure that the laundry schedule is carried out accordingly, instructing the staff on how to use the various cleaning products daily, draw to their attention the safety procedures during use.
- Control the charge of subcontractors accommodations & meals back charge on monthly basis.

### **GENERAL MANAGER**

### MOJA TUU LUXURY VILLAS & NATURAL RETREAT-ZANZIBAR, Tanzania

5 stars Resort 51 VILLAS

Aug 2018 -July 2020

### **GENERAL MANAGER**

Kiwengwa Beach Resort – Flash International Kiwi RESORTs -ZANZIBAR, Tanzania

Kiwengwa Beach Resort 5 stars Resort 125 rooms

June 2015 -May 2018

### **Hotel Manager**

Boudl Hotels & Resorts –Hotel Apartment (K.S.A)

### **Boudl Khorais 128 rooms & Boudl Olaya 142 rooms 4+ stars**

Jan 2013 - May 2015

Manage oversees the entire day-to-day operation related to Hotel, managing the crew on board, budgets in addition, achieving customers satisfactory to the standard.

Responsible for all over areas of service and presentation of all Hotel areas.

Ensure highest luxury delivery and smooth day-to-day operation in all guest service areas within Rooms Division including Reservations, hotel lobby, butler service, and switchboard. Highly effective in handling guest feedback and ensuring the highest levels of guest and colleagues' satisfaction.

Ensure all guest satisfaction and guest reviews online (Trip Advisers – Booking.com...etc.) increase rating and ranking online

Business developments International & local Market



Achievements (Certificate of excellence from Trip adviser)

Duties & Responsibilities

- Ensure that operating cost kept to a minimum.
- Keep an eye on details to improve the quality of service by continuously being creative
- Answer small queries from Clients via Website.
- Research new market opportunities.
- Map out and discover potential customers and competitors.
- Perform any other duties as may be assigned by the Management
- Welcome all arrivals and greet farewell to all departures
- Check all outlets, back areas, and offices
- Spot check the staff accommodation
- Overview general operation of Rooms Division
- Encourage Energy Saving
- Assist in the Sales and Reservation process of the resort if/when required

### **Deputy GM /Rooms**

Flash International Kiwi Resorts - Zanzibar (Tanzania) June 2010 - Nov. 2012 Kiwengwa Beach Resorts 5 stars 105 rooms / Chwaka Bay Resort 5\* 30 rooms/ Baobab Beach bungalow 5\* 105 rooms

### **Duties & Responsibilities**

- Continuously strives, with the team, to provide the Ultimate experience to all guests.
- Proactively anticipate guest needs and plans guest stays along with the team to surpass guest expectations.
- Handles all verbal and written guest feedback along with the team to ensure maximum guest satisfaction while protecting the company's interests.
- Manage the welcome and farewell experience for all guests in the lobby.
- Welcomes VIP guests to the hotel and alerts GM for special VIPs and Royal family member's bookings.
- Monitor the day-to-day show around requests conducted by the guest service team.
- Ensures full complies with all Leading Quality Assurance, Signature standards.
- Controls operating levels and efficiency in the department including holiday planning, duty rosters, and special events.
- Ensures that every colleague within the F&B / Rooms Division has a clear Individual Development
- Planning and organizing accommodation, catering, and other hotel services; Setting and achieving sales and profit targets (promoting and marketing the business and devising marketing management strategies); Managing budgets and controlling expenditure,
- Ensure efficient and effective hotel operational systems, processes, and policies
- Support management reporting information flow and business processes and organization planning

### **FRONT OFFICE MANAGER Position**

<u>HMH Group (Coral Plaza Alahsa) –</u> BOUTIQUE Hotel 5 stars (Saudi Arabia) Mar. 2009 - May 2010 <u>Flash International (Baobab Beach Bungalows) -</u> Resort 5 stars (Tanzania) Jun 2007 - Feb. 2009 <u>Flash International (Sea Club/Sea Life) -</u> Resort 5 stars (Egypt) Jun 2005 - May. 2007 <u>Calimera Moderna Beach,</u> Resort 5 stars (Egypt) Jan 2004 - May 2005

### **Duties & Responsibilities**

- Play a hand on a role with checking guests in /out of the hotel and cleaning rooms in the case of urgent guest arrivals.
- Maintain high visibility with employees and guests.
- Maintain up-to-date and detailed guest profiles and preferences.
- Develop and maintain, with the assistance of F&B, an ever-improving creative guest amenities program.
- Take charge of all guest complaints, reviews, and recoveries by ensuring appropriate follow-up to exceed guests' expectations and response within 48 hours.



- Take charge of the installation and updating of the System (Opera, Fidelio....) Rooms Management Systems.
- Ensure the Business Centre maintained in a clean and fully equipped manner at all times with the latest technology available.
- Liaise with external contractors, for Airport Arrivals, Transportation, Florist, and Laundry to ensure service and quality standards met at all times.
- Prepare the departmental budget that correctly reflects the hotel's business plan.
- Maintain correct procedures for hotel accounting, credit control and handling of financial transactions, and supply inventory relating to the Rooms Division.
- Actively participate in the Revenue and Credit meetings.

### **Front Office Supervisor**

Hilton Worldwide Hilton Sharm Waterfalls 5 stars (Egypt) Jun.1995- Nov.2003

Duties & Responsibilities

- Handle all guest queries and requests
- Know of all arrivals/departures and ensure guest names are used at all times
- Know the current availability situation at any given time, and also future availability
- Familiar with all hotel room types, numbers, layout, locations, rates
- Know the hotel ethos to assist with site inspections when requested
- Manage up-selling opportunities, email capture and other Front Office initiatives
- Drive core values to positively impact both Employee and Guest Satisfaction scores
- Represent and/or assist Front Office Manager in all necessary meetings, as required, to ensure effective inter-departmental communication
- Liaise with Front Office Manager on all issues/feedback raised in internal and external reports, and Sterling guest surveys
- Ensure all Front Office work areas (front and back of house) and equipment are clean and well
  maintained, and report defective materials/equipment to Front Office Manager
- Monitor pre-registered arrivals and ensure all no shows are checked out and charged
- Meet and welcome regular and VIP guests
- Ensure Front Door entrance is covered at all times and bell staff are posted
- Ensure compliance with hotel credit policy and Standard Financial Procedures

### **OPENING EXPERINCE**

1-	Hilton Waterfalls	1999	Sharm Elshiekh - Egypt
2-	Calimera Moderna Beach	2004	Sharm Elshiekh - Egypt
3-	Baobab Beach Resort	2007 / 2010 /2012	Zanzibar - Tanzania
4-	Coral Plaza Al Ahsa	2009	Saudi Arabia
4-	Kiwengwa Beach Resort	2016	Zanzibar -Tanzania
5-	Moja Tuu Luxury Villas & Natural Retreat 2018		Zanzibar - Tanzania

- To take projects to tender, manage and the process
- Compare quotes and compile budgets
- Put time lines for projects together using Microsoft Projects or similar (plan charts etc.)
- Understand the requirements set out by the, Owner, Chief Engineer when explaining projects
- Follow the oversee construction.
- Read and oversee the implementation of MEP drawings
- Provide reports and updates as projects develop
- Basic Quantity Surveying skills and the ability to put in house building budgets together
- Installing Lighting Conductors to twelve rooms'
- Building additional staff accommodation
- Facilitating the logistics and assisting the Chief Engineer with the Renewable Project
- Completing an outdoor lighting Project
- . Re thatching roofs around the Beach Pool area
- Electrical upgrades
- Oversee and control all the preopening planning for the Hotel:
- Define General Operative Manual: Hotel concept, services and facilities.
- Organize the recruitment and training process for the future operational departments.
- Organize the correct planning for each operational department.

- Ensure the correct elaboration of operational standards, manuals and procedures.
- Ensure the well planning in logistics and procurement.
- Ensure a smooth transition from construction to operation.
- Ensure a successful official opening.
- Oversee and control all the general operations of the hotel and activities related thereto.
- Oversee the management of all the departments of the hotel\*
- Oversee the daily functions of the hotel by monitoring each Head of Department.

### **International Experience**

Egypt, Saudi Arabia, Bahrain (Task Force), Tanzania, Zanzibar Island (Indian Ocean) Multinational Staff leading and managing

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree Hotel Management at High Institute of Tourism & Hotel 6 October City Egypt Completion Date: May 1995 Study for 4 years Hotel management High school or equivalent, Math Science Department at High School Cairo Egypt Completion Date: May 1991 4 Years study on Math science Dept.

### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic, English, German, Italian, Swahili

### **TRAINING**

Health and Safety Assurance (2007). First Aid, Front Office Training Course - Telephone skills (Professional & Advanced Skills), Handling Complaints - Steps for the Best Customer Service Handling and Making Groups Reservation, Selling Skills - Leadership Skills

Train the Trainers, Orientation (Basic Meeting Guest Expectations) Customer Focus - Managing Operations - Adaptability - Polite - Outgoing - Personable - Understanding the Business - Team Building - Planning for Business - Leading People- Valuing Diversity - Influencing Outcomes - Drive for Results - Manage multi nationality team

### **SKILLS**

- Management skills / Negotiation skills / Administrational skills / Organizational & time management skills / Computer skills / Communication skills - written and verbal / leadership skills
- Strategic planning and operations providing the future growth planning and decision-making.
- Building and managing client relationships
- P&L management for the region
- Legal & compliance ensuring local regulatory and compliance

#### HOBBIES

Walking – Reading – Swimming – Drawing – Internet Search

### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

28 Alfady Street, Haram 11121 Giza, Egypt

Cell: +255737586251 +20 1007415736 / Skype ID: malimalit

Email: MALIMALIT@GMAIL.COM / LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/malimalit/

### **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Place and date of birth: Misr Elqadima, Egypt – February 22, 1972 Married, father of two sons & one daughter Military completed

### **REFERENCE:**

Magdy Takla: CEO Meeting Point Management +201005004084
 Ammar Kanaan: Consultant at Auris Hotels <u>A.KANAAN@AURIS-HOTELS.COM</u> +971509226551
 Kaeim Helmy General manager Hilton Hotels <u>KARIM.HELMY@HILTON.COM</u> +20123240592